January 1943.
the survivors of the
battle of Gudalcanal
were taken to Melbourne. Australia.
Here. they would recover and
wait while the United States
built up its military forces.
In spite of the
victory of Gudalcanal.
Japan still held the vast territory
surrounding its homeland.
It would take close to a year
to build the force large enough
to launch the next major American
offensive in the Pacific.
Meanwhile. when the marines
docked in Melbourne.
news of their success
had preceded them.
We got to Melbourne
and they were calling
us saviors of Australia.
You know what.
it was music to our ears.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
When we arrived in Melbourne.
we had no idea what Australians
were supposed to be like.
or what the country was
supposed to be like.
All we knew is we had been
unloaded there in heaven.
You gotta keep in mind
that the Australian-New
Zealand army core.
they were in Africa and...
so. there was a shortage of men.
And all these gals hadn't had
any attention for a long time.
and we endeavor to do a good job.
I bet that was the best liberty *
** we had ever got.
It was perfect.
It was counseling on your mind
that this haven that we were
in was not gonna last forever.
You're still US and in the marine
and you knew that there was
a war going on and we...
knew that we would be into
it in a very short time.
Where we didn't know.
but we knew we were going.
We've been swallowed
by the jungle and
5.000 japs waiting to kill us.
- So the japs got us surrounded.
- Is that what's buggin' you?
Jap navy sails up and down this
slot every night and plasters us.
Bud...Bud. we gotta go.
Come on. bud! Come on!
Our battalion will join Hanneken's in
our old position south of the airfield.
They might pull Hanneken.
And that is gonna leave us alone.
singled up on the line.
I got the whole fucking Jap
army headed your way. over.
Japs left. crawling in!
I'm putting you in
for a medal. John.
Sir. anybody bring in
Sergeant Rodriguez last night?
Get your gear and
stand by to stand by.
We're finally leaving
this shithole.
So how bad was it?
Cause I heard it was bad.
From who?
I mean before you got here.
have you ever even heard of this place?
Everybody's heard of Guadalcanal
and the 1st marine division.
You're heroes back home.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Heroes! Heroes!
Welcome to australia. mates.
What the hell is this?
Well done. Well done.
Yay for the yankees.
- Yay!
- Welcome down under.
G'day. handsome.
We love you.
G'day there. mate.
Do you believe this?
We love you!
How many japs you kill. yank?
You kill many japs?
Killed any japs?
Let's go. Disembark the truck.
Find your company areas.
Where are we?
Keep moving.
Make sure you got all your gear.
Find your area.
Keep moving all  the way through.
Let's go. Find your areas.
Make sure to store those
M1 rifles now!
Andrews. you're on mess. Move it.
It ain't no wrigley field.
Man on p.A.:
Attention in the area.
All arriving personnel.
this is your billeting area.
You will be directed
by your company.
First squad. let's go.
Grab those packs.
Oh. the hell with this.
I'm gonna sleep for a few days.
Better take a look at this.
The m.P.S are just giving up.
Can they do that?
Everyone's going awol.
Nobody's stopping them.
Oh. I've got to be a part of this.
- Marine: Whoo. freedom!
- All right.
Melbourne here we come.
Let's hit the streets.
Hey. buddy. rest up. All right?
Mmm.
I have something.
It's like st. Mark's on woodward.
All saints on north hermitage.
It's as pure as every
church bell that ever rang.
Straight ahead. Give it a try.
- It's wonderful.
- Sorry. excuse me.
The beers?
Here. here and here.
Whiskey.
Gin.
Rum.
Vodka.
Rye.
Brandy. bourbon
And vermouth.
- And you call that...
- A blockbuster.
You're sure gonna be
trouble tonight. cobber.
- Here you go. manny.
- To manny.
Never thought you'd
down that. mate.
Right now we could down anything.
Aren't you supposed to be
in africa fighting rommel?
Somebody has to keep the
peace at home.
Let you yanks get your proper r&r.
Quite a lot of you here now.
Just arrived today?
- Must be thousands.
- Tens of thousands.
How many. mates?
Enough for a cricket team.
Enough to make our beer run
dry and our girls run loose.
Have to fuck the king himself to find a
taxi you warriors haven't commandeered.
I'd say it's a bit more
like a gang of roaches.
Every step we take. and bloody hell.
there's another yank under our boot.
I'm guessing this is one yank we
don't have to worry about anymore.
Hey. if it weren't for us
you'd be guzzling sake
With a pair of chopsticks up your ass.
you stupid fuck.
Okay okay. that's it.
Yeah right. you're all tommy
mix who saved the day.
It's okay. Why don't
you get out of here?
This one hits the turps.
first thing out he's having a blue.
Another dumb drunk who
thinks he can fight.
Let us buy you the
next round of drinks.
Otherwise what kind of
hosts would we be?
Alan. another round of
drinks for the cowboy yanks.
Whoo!
Oh. yank here.
Looking to see the town.
Oh. hello.
Hello. beautiful.
Visitor down under;
speak the same language.
Hey!
Hey. beautiful.
Oh. what the hell's he doing?
Where's that tram go? - That's the
preston line. He'll end up in perth.
- Oh hey. leckie. come on!
- Hey. leckie. what the hell?
Excuse me. sir. Ma'am.
I apologize.
Pardon me. Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
- Hey. leckie!
Whoa!  Attaboy. leck.
Are you proposing already. yank?
I'm proposing that you
take walk with me.
You never know what
the future may bring.
You know what take a walk means?
Oh. ma'am.
Ma'am. miss--
Miss. I'm a foreigner
on your shores.
Forgive my ignorance
of your customs. but...
My invitation remains an offer.
Ha.
You're a bold one sotted.
Let's see you in the light of day.
Collect me at home.
Being sober would be a plus.
I'm stella. in case you were
wondering what to call me.
Ah.
Stella is it?
Well. you've got guts. leckie.
Thank you very much.
That made my night.
- You'd better laminate that piece of paper.
- That made my night.
- Gonna be good?
- I'll say.
Shh. be quiet.
Hit it.
Company dismissed.
Let me tell you something.
sergeant.
Stumbling around camp
like the town stiff
Is not acceptable behavior.
Not anymore.
Can't help but notice I'm
not alone in this. sir.
Well. you are in one respect.
You are about to be awarded
the medal of honor.
President roosevelt
found you worthy.
Congratulations. old man.
You're about to go where very
few marines have ever been.
Oh. hey hey! Here here.
Oh. shit.
This is-- I'm sorr
Yeah. all right.
Listen.
Get yourself a big breakfast
and a pot of coffee
And you come back here
when you're respectable.
It's not gonna do to have you
heave all over your own citation.
This is the highest honor that our
country can award a serviceman.
But from now on.
You try and act like it's yours.
Yes. sir.
Well. go.
Aw. jeez.
* you're just an
angel in disguise *
* who wandered down from up above *
* you're just a heavenly
surprise *
* who came to earth
for me to love *
* 'cause introduction to an angel *
* is more than thrilling *
* it leaves me high... *
The articles of war?
That's what I'm calling 'em.
He's been going on about this
Since long before you came along.
See. gwenie's dad. my son.
he's over there in burma
Showing the japs what side is up.
I'm in charge of gwenie's honor.
A manual of arms.
My grandfather would want
the same understanding.
Let's get this understood.
Hit him with it. girl.
Article I:
General provisions.
Hands off the merchandise.
You've memorized this?
See. I'm the merchandise.
Hand off. aye aye. sir.
Article ii:
Hands off the merchandise.
Meaning there'll be none of that.
There's no problem there.
I'm not much of a dancer. sir.
Um. article iii:
Punishments for
violating one and two.
It'll be swift and unflinching.
Don't for a moment
think otherwise. son.
Yes. sir.
Make a hole. Come on.
Drink it out of the
glass without spilling.
That's right. Take your time.
Move closer. A little close.
- Closer.
- Come on.
Closer. Closer.
A little closer.
It's hard. Come on.
M.P.S just pulled up.
You've got to get out of here.
Every marine in this place is awol.
I'd say that's why they're here.
Listen up.
Every marine in this establishment
Will produce a liberty pass or will
return immediately to his billet.
Oh. come on!
What's this then?
There's no problem.
I've got a pass.
But still. why don't I escort
gwen out the back. sir?
- M.P.: You're going back to your billet.
- Good night. gramps.
- Don't wait up.
- M.P.: Show me your pass.
Come on. let's go.
Come on. mo.
Saddle up. pardner. - Stealing an m.
P.'s jeep? Are you kidding me?
- ( starts engine - come on. mo.  Hop in.
You can't do this shit.
john. Not now.
Remember what chesty told you.
Don't screw this up.
Left.
March.
Line halt.
Detail halt.
Sir. detail is formed.
For extraordinary heroism
and conspicuous gallantry.
Sergeant john basilone.
While at great risk to
his own life.
Fought valiantly to check a savage
And determined japanese assault
While serving the 1st
battalion. 7th marines
In guadalcanal on
October 24 and 25. 1942.
Sergeant john basilone
is hereby awarded
The medal of honor.
Left as we go.
Right face.
Company right hut.
Face right.
So what's your name then?
Bob.
Sobered up. are you. bob?
I'm no fool.
These are for you.
I hope you're hungry.
Man on radio:...Created
by the announcement
That president roosevelt and
winston churchill
Have met at casablanca
and completed...
- Stella: This is bob.
- Leckie.
Bob leckie.
Shake hands with my father baba.
what a grip.
An american grip. eh?
This is my mama.
This is a yank.
Skin and bones.
Like a skeleton. Like a rail.
Stella. his jacket. Ella.
I thought we were
going for a stroll.
Good news. bob.
You're staying for dinner.
I am?
One word of an american coming
to call and that was that.
This is like a thanksgiving.
Oh. what is that?
It's a holiday roosevelt made of
the fourth Thursday of November.
Everyone sits at the table.
eats turkey and argues.
roosevelt is a great man.
You eat as much as you like.
eh? Ella.
The beans are from the garden.
You didn't touch the feta.
We save it for tomorrow. huh?
Nay. mama. I'll start cleaning up.
You see? Good girl. my stella.
Good greek girl.
You're on your own now.
I think I can handle this one.
So. mama.
What's a greek girl like
you doing in melbourne?
Oh. you don't care about that.
No no no. don't go officer on me.
You're not australian.
No no. I come from the old country.
Smyrna.
That was sacked by the turks.
wasn't it?
You know about that?
Um. I read a lot.
The turks invaded in 1922
and burned it down.
All gone.
If you survived.
you fled like my mama and me.
But we made it down to the docks.
We swam to a ship.
The captain took us onboard
And sailed us to piraeus.
He saved our lives.
But our home was gone.
So where do we go?
We come here.
We live. we work. we find love.
So now you must tell
about your home.
- Yeah. about america.
- No no no.
Not america. America
we see in the movies.
Your family. - Well.
seems like we both escaped disaster.
I fled the leckie household.
How many in the household?
Mama had five girls. three boys.
Oh. okto babies. Your lucky mama.
I don't know if she'd agree.
She was almost 40 by the time I came along.
She was worn out by then.
I think they all were.
But it's a blessing.
so many children.
Well. marion and foddy leckie.
they didn't want eight kids.
Oh no? They should stop?
They didn't want the
beautiful baby son?
I was last. Lasts least.
Oh. bob. You know nothing.
By the time I met nicola
It was almost too
late to make babies.
Not that we didn't try. eh?
Eh. relax.
That girl in the kitchen.
my only blessing.
I prayed for more.
But god said no.
Nothing u can do when god say no.
So where do you stay
with the marines. huh?
They put us in the stadium
where you play cricket.
What?  You will stay here tonight.
Stella. get the bed ready
in the spare room. - Okay.
I can't do that.
I could never repay you.
You can help clear the
vines from the roof.
Yes. you will do that.
You will make this your home.
Twist a guy's arm.
Oh. dear god.
Oh. god.
No no no. you stay right there.
I think we should
give it another go.
Okay. sure. Sure. me too.
But even americans need. uh...
Oh. a wait before they reload.
It's okay.
I'm going nowhere.
Why did you have to
flee your family?
Oh...
My family.
Not happy bunch. my family.
Why not?
Something in our bones.
Did your brothers go into
the service to get away too?
One of my brothers was too old.
The other died when I was a kid.
That's terrible.
My father's been crippled
in the head ever since.
We're not exactly the
judge hardy family.
I swear. I'm just waiting for
the clock to hit midnight
And my sanity bell goes ringing.
I had a brother who died too.
You did?
No one talks about him.
He was a baby. just a few
days old and didn't live.
Mama got sick and wasn't
able to have any more.
We start by restoring their bodies.
They rest. They play.
Then we work on their pride.
We remind them they're marines.
Then we replenish our supplies.
See. all of that takes money.
I understand.
It's a hell of a lot
easier to raise money
When there's a face behind it
And a heroic story attached to it.
Like yours.
I don't feel like a hero. sir.
You're not getting it.
All right.
Think of us out there on that line.
You know what we need--
New weapons. new gear.
better motor transport.
Yes. sir.
Selling u.S. War bonds
Is just as important.
just as life saving.
As what you did on guadalcanal.
Now pack your seabag.
You're going home
Home?
How many u.S.
War bonds you gonna sell
Stomping around the
solomons with us?
Go on. Get it done. sergeant.
Oh.
I liked that.
Shame on me.
I got you something.
Stockings?
Real silk?
I'll wear them only for you.
Wait wait wait wait. There's more.
This...
Is for everyone.
oh no.
- Leg of lamb.
- No.
How? How did you get it?
- I'm not gonna tell you.
- Why not?
I think you should
kiss me first. - How?
- How?
- I can't remember.
I can't get a leg of lamb.
But you do?
American ingenuity and a
few packs of lucky strikes.
"nicholas genkos-- wounded.
Is that theodora genkos' nephew?
I don't know.
Baba checks the casualty
reports for greek names.
"alexi stavrapolous."
What's happened to alexi?
"killed in action."
I grew up with alexi.
He lived two streets over.
Change your shirt. nicola.
We'll take them the spanikopita.
I'd like to go.
Pay my respects.
if they're friends of yours.
- This is my friend bob.
- My condolences.
Stella and alexi.
They were friends every
since they were children.
He was her friend.
It's no good. bob.
Mama is still up.
The greek boys are gone.
More and more every day--
All of stella's friends from
when she grew up.
I prayed for them.
And for their families.
Do you go to church. bob?
- St. Mary's.
- Mmm.
What kind of church?
Catholic.
I like the early morning mass.
Less people.
Hmm. we need prayers.
How are we going to make
it through these years
If we don't pray?
We are so lucky to
have you with us. bob.
To have a young man in the house.
I like you.
Stella. she likes you.
Baba. he always
wanted a son like you.
I am going to pray that
you come back to us.
That's a good thing to pray for.
Let's get your squads going!
Pack up that gear anlet's go!
What?  You thought uncle sam was gonna
pay for your great debauch forever?
- Officer: Move out!
- Semper fi.
Better gear up. brother.
Time to get back in shape.
The m1 is better.
Thers no contest.
- Runner: Okay. so show us.
- Okay. ready ready.
oh!
Eight rounds over five.
No. I will still
keep my springfield.
Jesus christ. it's like
talking to an old lady.
Fine. You know what?
Keep your cane.
- I will keep my cane.
- I'll will take the m1
Because it beats the hell
out of the springfield.
No no no no. The 03's are
still more accurate.
- Exactly exactly.
- No no. they're slower.
- Target in sight.
- Watch him miss.
- Do it!
- Come on. gibson.
Come on. gibson.
bull's-eye!
Hey!  Hey!
What are you doing?
You just shot some
poor farmer's cow!
It was gonna be steak anyway.
Not if it's a dairy cow. you idiot.
good shot. gibson.
What kind of morons
have you become?
Did you see that?
I've never seen that.
You will be given
one sack of raisins.
You will be given one
sack of uncooked rice.
A japanese soldier can live
on that for three weeks.
You will March the 100 miles
Back to melbourne
And be in the arms of your
aussie girlfriends
In three days.
Fall in. column of two.
Standby to move out.
Let's go. Fall in.
Move out!
H-2-1. drop your cocks and
grab your socks.
Formation in 20 minutes.
Come on. let's move.
On your feet. let's go.
Come on. shake it out.
Let's do it.
On your feet. Let's move.
Fuck!
God!
You first.
Mmm!
Oh. sweet jesus. that feels good.
- Couple of doors down.
- Just right up?
- Yeah.
- Oh. thank you.
- Take this with you.
- No...
You have to go away. bob.
Please don't come here anymore.
I told mama and baba already
That you got your orders and you left.
You couldn't say goodbye.
You lied?
I'm fairly crazy about you. robert.
I think you know that.
I thought so. yeah.
But...
I don't want to have
a baby with you.
Uh...
Are you pregnant?
- No.  No.
- You're not?
Bob. you and I aren't
going to have a family.
And we're not going to get married.
And you are never coming
back to melbourne.
You're dumping me because you
think I'm gonna get killed?
Bob...
If you don't come back to us.
I don't just lose you.
Mama does too.
I can't do that to her
and I won't let you.
She's lost so much already. bob.
She's praying for you
to come back to us.
She can save her breath.
Leckie. Leckie. god love you.
- Come here.
- Fuck off.
No. seriously. I've got
to piss like terrible.
You've got to cover for me. okay?
I can't. Drunk as a skunk.
One minute. that's
all I need. Come on.
Come on. Thank you.
Leckie. what are you doing?
Manning this fucking post.
lieutenant.
- Are you out of your mind?
- I'm the fucking guard on guard duty.
You pull a fucking
sidearm on an officer?
Lieutenant. I went for a quick piss.
Leckie was just covering.
- You fucking prick!
- Stand at attention.
- Fuck you!
- I said stand at attention!
And I said fuck you!
* don't sit under the apple tree *
* with anyone else but me *
* no no no. don't sit
under the apple tree *
* with anyone else but me *
* till I come marching home. *
yay. ma.
- Run. ma!
- Good hit. ma.
Yes. auntie. that's a six.
So I guess it's sort
of like baseball. huh?
What happens in baseball?
Well. in baseball.
You hit a ball and
you run to a base.
Then you run to the
next base if you can.
You keep going to the next base.
If you get to enough
bases you score a run.
Sounds like rounders.
We play that in school.
Looks like someone is
hunting for you. cobber.
Hey. it's my turn.
Shit.
- Your unit?
- How company. 1st marines.
Report to your c.O.
No later than 2400.
I trust you marines got
your heads back together.
I'm on orders from
2nd marine division.
Lieutenant lebec has
got the platoon now.
And I want him to
inherit a solid outfit
So I volunteered you
for reassignment
To the battalion
intelligence section
You're booting us?
Not you--
Leckie.
Fuck.
So. a little light.
Yeah.
How about if an engine catches fire
And you dump in the pacific?
Swim around for days. weeks.
get strafeby jap zeroes.
Finally the navy picks you up.
Think about how many war
bonds you'd sell then.
Probably give you another medal.
You're gonna look up katie. right?
First chance I get.
I've been sending my poker
winnings home to her.
Hey. 700 of that is mine.
that's the good
thing about leaving--
I won't lose anymore money to you.
Wish you were coming with me.
I think that's you.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm